A Guide to the Papers of Rita Mae Brown 1929-2001
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- Literary Papers and Manuscripts
  - Screenplays and Teleplays arranged by Title
    - "Passing Through" Script Outline Edited 1992 Dec 16-17 (Box 89)
    - "Passing Through" Script Outline Edited 1993 Jan 13-14 (Box 89)
    - "Passing Through" Script Outline Edited 1993 Jan 15 (Box 89)
    - "Passing Through" Revised Script Outline--Final and Notes 1993 Feb 1 (Box 89)
    - "Passing Through" Original Draft 1993 Feb 17 (Box 90)
    - "Passing Through" Original Draft--Revised, with changes and corrections [1993 Feb 18?], 100 pages (Box 90)
    - "Passing Through" Original Draft--Revised, with changes and corrections [1993 Feb 18?], Electrostatic copy, 100 pages (Box 90)
    - "Passing Through" 1st Set Revisions--Edited 1993 Mar 19, 95 pages (Box 90)
    - "Passing Through" 1st Set Revisions--Final 1993 Mar 22, 95 pages (Box 90)
    - "Passing Through" Draft One Final 1993 Mar 22, 113 pages (Box 90)
    - "Passing Through" 2nd Set Revisions--Final Proof Copy 1993 Apr 13 (Box 90)
    - "Passing Through" 2nd Set Revisions--Final 1993 Apr (Box 90)
    - "Passing Through"--Changes Final 1993 May 6 (Box 90)
    - "Passing Through"--Notes (through August 20) and Correspondence 1992 Apr-1993 Feb (Box 90)
    - "Power City" Electrostatic Copy of the Published Book by Beth Ann Harmon 1988 (Box 91)
    - "Power City" Notes and Correspondence 1988-1989 (Box 91)
      re a possible screenplay
    - "Rescue of Lauren" Screenplay by Gordon Trueblood and Correspondence 1989-1990 (Box 91)
      re a possible rewrite
    - "Rich Men, Single Women" Story Outline [ca. 1988 Dec], 22 pages (Box 91)
    - "Rich Men, Single Women" [Original Draft ?], with changes and corrections 1989 [Feb?], 87 pages (Box 91)
    - "Rich Men, Single Women" Original Draft, with changes and corrections 1989 [Feb ?], 92 pages (Box 91)
    - "Rich Men, Single Women" First Draft, Clean Copy 1989 Mar 23, 123 pages (Box 91)
    - "Rich Men, Single Women" First Draft, First Cut [1989 Mar 23], 119 pages (Box 91)
    - "Rich Men, Single Women" 1989 Mar, 125 pages (Box 92)
    - "Rich Men, Single Women" Second Draft 1989 Jun 6, 130 pages (Box 92)
    - "Rich Men, Single Women" [Second Draft ?] 1989 Jun 9, 125 pages (Box 92)
    - "Rich Men, Single Women" Second Draft, with changes and corrections [1989 Jun], 124 pages; 2 folders (Box 92)
    - "Rich Men, Single Women" Shooting Script 1989 Oct 12-24, 149 pages (Box 92)
    - "Rich Men, Single Women"--Contract, Character Sketches, Correspondence, and Chapter Summaries of the Book 1988-1989 (Box 92)
    - "Rich Men, Single Women"--Credit Arbitration 1989 (Box 92)
    - "Ride--Off" Various Drafts and Revisions 1989 (Box 93)
    - "Rubyfruit Jungle" Screenplay by Rita Mae Brown and Arnie Reisman, First Draft 1976 Dec 3, 162 pages (Box 93)
    - "Rubyfruit Jungle"Screenplay by Bruce Campbell, Paul C. Morrissey, and Todd Bachmann 1995 Nov 15, 146 pages (Box 93)
    - "Selma, Lord, Selma" Second Draft Polish by Michael and Alice Arlen 1989 Feb (Box 93)
    - "Selma, Lord, Selma" Original Revision by Rita Mae Brown 1989 (Box 93)
    - "Selma, Lord, Selma" Further Revision Copy 1989, 138 pages (Box 93)
    - "Selma, Lord, Selma" Original Third Draft 1989 Aug 1, 143 pages (Box 93)
    - "Selma, Lord, Selma" Third Draft 1989 Aug 1, 143 pages (Box 94)
    - "Selma, Lord, Selma" Third Draft with Revisions for the Fourth 1989 Aug 1, 143 pages (Box 94)
    - "Selma, Lord, Selma" Third Draft--Final Revised Copy 1989 Aug 1, 138 pages, with additional pages 1-63 (Box 94)
    - "Selma, Lord, Selma" Fourth Draft [1989 Oct], 117 pages (Box 94)
    - "Selma, Lord, Selma" Fourth Draft, with Further Revisions, with NBC notes [1989 Oct], 109 pages (Box 94)
    - "Selma, Lord, Selma" Fourth Draft--Final Rough [1989 Dec], 112 pages (Box 94)
    - "Selma, Lord, Selma" Fourth Draft 1989 Dec 12, 116 pages (Box 94)
    - "Shannon's Deal" by John Sayles Final Draft--Pilot for NBC 1988 Dec 6, 112 pages (Box 95)
    - "Shannon's Deal" by John Sayles--"Custody" Episode Final Draft Revised 1989 Nov 27, 58 pages (Box 95)
    - "Shannon's Deal"--"Wrongful Death" Episode by Tom Rickman 1990 (Box 95)
    - "Shannon's Deal"--"The Lucy Story" Episode by Rita Mae Brown ca. 1990-1992 (Box 95)
    - "Six of One"--A Treatment with Scene by Scene Breakdown on Index Cards 1984 Oct 16 (Box 95)
    - "Southern Discomfort" [Original?] First Draft, with author's changes and corrections [ca. 1984?], 170 pages (Box 96)
    - "Southern Discomfort" First Draft, with author's changes and corrections [ca. 1984?], 154 pages (Box 96)
    - "Southern Discomfort" First Draft, with author's changes and corrections [ca. 1984?], 154 pages (Box 96)
    - "Southern Discomfort" [First Draft Final ?] [ca. 1984], 144 pages (Box 96)
    - "Southern Discomfort" First Draft [ca. 1984], Bound Copy, 144 pages; 2 copies in 2 folders (Box 96)
    - "Southern Discomfort" First Draft [ca. 1984], Bound Copy, 144 pages (Box 97)
    - "Southern Discomfort" Correspondence and Proposals 1985-1991 (Box 97)
    - "Southern Discomfort" Notecards with Scene by Scene Breakdowns n.d. (Box 97)
    - "Southern Exposures" Character Sketches, Genealogies, and Summary 1990 [Jul?] (Box 97)
    - "Southern Exposure" Prologue, Story Lines, etc." 1990 Aug 1 (Box 97)
    - "Southern Exposures" Prologue and Story Lines, Rough Edited [1990] Sep 17 (Box 97)
    - "Southern Exposures"--Television Bible 1990 Aug-Sep (Box 97)
    - "Southern Exposures"--Correspondence, usually with enclosures attached 1990 May-Dec (Box 97)
    - "Sweet Surrender" Original Draft and Notes 1986, 133 pages (Box 98)
    - "Sweet Surrender" First Draft with author's changes and corrections 1986 Jun 1, 145 pages (Box 98)
    - "Sweet Surrender" First Draft 1986 Jun 1, 150 pages (Box 98)
    - "Sweet Surrender' First Draft 1986 Jul 11, 101 pages (Box 98)
    - "Sweet Surrender" Act I, with Notes by Rita Mae Brown 1986 Jul 11 (Box 98)
    - "Sweet Surrender" Act II, with author's changes and corrections, with notes dated July 30, 1986 1986 Aug (Box 98)
    - "Sweet Surrender" First Draft, with author's changes and corrections 1986 Sep 7, 125 pages (Box 98)
      including letters from Brown dated August 19 and September 5, 1986
    - "Sweet Surrender" 1986 Sep 7, Bound Typescript, 125 pages (Box 98)
    - "Sweet Surrender" 1986 Sep 7, Bound Typescript, 125 pages (Box 99)
    - "Sweet Surrender" First Draft, 125 pages, with Notes 1986 Nov 3, 125 pages (Box 99)
    - "Sweet Surrender" Early Draft with Notes and Scene by Scene Breakdown 1986 Dec 23 (Box 99)
    - "Sweet Surrender" First Draft, First Revisions, with changes and corrections by the author, including Character Sketches 1987 Feb 3, 113 pages (Box 99)
    - "Sweet Surrender" First Draft, First Revisions 1987 Feb 3, Bound Copy, 127 pages (Box 99)
    - "Sweet Surrender" First Draft, First Revisions 1987 Feb 3, 129 pages (Box 99)
    - "Sweet Surrender" First Draft, First Revisions 1987 Feb 3, 129 pages (Box 99)
    - "Sweet Surrender" First Draft, First Revisions 1987 Feb 3, 129 pages; 4 copies in 4 folders (Box 100)
    - "Table Dancing" Original Screenplay by John Carlen, with note to Rita Mae Brown from Robert Cortez, dated June 10, 1986 1985 Dec 23 (Box 100)
    - "Table Dancing" Original Screenplay by John Carlen, Revised Draft 1986 Feb 12 (Box 100)
    - "Table Dancing'--Correspondence and Notes, including Scene Breakdowns and Character Sketches 1986 Jun-1987 Jan, 2 folders (Box 100)
    - "Table Dancing" Scene Breakdowns--First and Second Set 1987 Mar 3 (Box 101)
    - "Table Dancing" Scene by Scene Breakdown ca. 1987 Mar, 117 pages (Box 101)
    - "Table Dancing" First Draft, with author's changes and corrections 1987 May 14, 122 pages (Box 101)
    - "Table Dancing" First Draft, with author's changes and corrections 1987 May [15?], 130 pages (Box 101)
    - "Table Dancing" First Draft 1987 May 18, 130 pages (Box 101)
    - "Table Dancing", with Notes by Robert Cortez and Rita Mae Brown 1987 May 18, 130 pages (Box 101)
    - "Table Dancing" [First Draft Revised ?] [1987 Sep], 119 pages (Box 101)
    - "Table Dancing" Second Draft 1987 Sep, 129 pages (Box 101)
    - "Table Dancing" Second Draft 1987 Sep 11, 137 pages (Box 102)
    - "Table Dancing" Second Draft 1987 Sep 11, Bound Copy, 137 pages; 2 copies in 2 folders (Box 102)
    - "Table Dancing--Correspondence and Research 1987 Jun-Aug (Box 102)
    - "Tales from the Crypt--Werewolf Concert" by Rita Mae Brown and Scott Nimerfro 1991 Nov-1992, 2 folders (Box 102)
    - "Thursdays 'Til Nine" Scene by Scene Breakdown 1982, 142 pages; 2 copies in 2 folders (Box 102)
    - "Thursdays 'Til Nine" First Draft [1983 Jan 17], 211 pages; 2 folders (Box 103)
    - "Thursdays 'Til Nine"--Notes, Outline and Correspondence 1982-1983 (Box 103)
    - "Tom Bass Story" Idea 1991-1993 (Box 103)
    - "The Wall: K-9 Segment" First Draft 1993 Nov 11, Manuscript and Typescript Copies (Box 103)
    - "The Wall: K-9 Segment" First Draft Revisions and Final 1993 (Box 103)
    - "The Wall: K-9 Segment" Contract, Correspondence, Character Sketches, and Outline 1993-1994 (Box 103)
    - "Whistling Dixie" First Draft by Rita Mae Brown and Elizabeth Wilson 1985 Aug 7, Spiral Bound Copy, 115 pages (Box 103)
    - "Whistling Dixie" First Draft, includes some notes, by Rita Mae Brown and Elizabeth Wilson 1985 Aug 7, Spiral Bound Copy, 115 pages (Box 103)
    - "Whistling Dixie" First Draft, by Rita Mae Brown and Eliabeth Wilson 1985 Aug 7, Spiral Bound Copy, 115 pages; 2 copies in 2 folders (Box 104)
    - "Whistling Dixie" First Draft, by Rita Mae Brown and Elizabeth Wilson 1985 Aug 7, Bound Copy, 115 pages (Box 104)
    - "Witch Hunt"--Correspondence, Character Sketches, Outline, and Scene by Scene Breakdown 1991-1992 (Box 104)
  - Articles and Book Reviews by Rita Mae Brown, Interviews with Brown, and other Literary Work by her
    - Articles about Rita Mae Brown 1976-1999, n.d., 2 folders (Box 104)
    - Articles by Rita Mae Brown, including relevant correspondence 1975-1988, 2 folders (Box 104)
    - Articles by Rita Mae Brown, including relevant correspondence 1992-2000, n.d., 2 folders (Box 105)
    - Articles by Rita Mae Brown-- Albemarle Magazine, including correspondence 1981, 1991-1998, 4 folders (Box 105)
    - Articles by Rita Mae Brown--"A Change of Work is Rest" 1994 (Box 105)
      the essay re A Day in the Life for the Writer's Guild of America, East
    - Articles and Notes by Rita Mae Brown 1970, n.d. (Box 105)
      re Class and Sexism
    - Articles by Rita Mae Brown-- Hark to the Line Newsletter 1998-2000, n.d. (Box 106)
    - Articles by Rita Mae Brown--Prospective articles for "Kisses and Revolution" ca. 1971-1974 (Box 106)
    - Articles by Rita Mae Brown--"Lavender Manace" included in The Reader's Companion to U.S. Women's History and Ms.; includes correspondence 1994-1995 (Box 106)
    - Articles 1981-1997, n.d. (Box 106)
      re Martina Navratilova, Judy Nelson, and Other Friends and Associates
    - Articles-- Mirabella1989 (Box 106)
    - Articles by Rita Mae Brown-- Ms. Magazine, including correspondence 1986-1999 (Box 106)
    - Articles by Rita Mae Brown--"Queen For a Day" 197[5] Oct 8 (Box 106)
    - Articles 1993-1999 (Box 106)
      re Sneaky Pie's Mysteries
    - Articles 1984-1994, n.d. (Box 106)
      re Story Ideas
    - Articles by Rita Mae Brown--"Tally Ho" for Sports Illustrated 1986-1987 (Box 106)
    - Articles by Rita Mae Brown-- Vogue"Travel", including correspondence 1984-1998 (Box 106)
    - Article by Rita Mae Brown--"The Woman-Identified Woman" 1970 May 1 (Box 106)
    - Book Reviews written by Rita Mae Brown 1979-1996, n.d., 4 folders (Box 107)
    - Book Reviews written by Rita Mae Brown-- Vice Versa in The Los Angeles Times1995 (Box 107)
    - "Foreword" to Our Right to Love: A Lesbian Resource Book1990 and 1994 (Box 107)
    - Interviews with Rita Mae Brown, includes correspondence 1981-2000, n.d., 3 folders (Box 107)
    - Interview with Rita Mae Brown 1994 (Box 108)
      re the Biography of Martina Navratilova by Gilda Zwerman
    - Interview with Rita Mae Brown conducted by Paul D. Cain 1995 Oct (Box 108)
    - "Introduction" by Rita Mae Brown to Colcorton by Edith Pope 1989-1990 (Box 108)
    - "Introduction" by Rita Mae Brown to Willa Cather's Short Story Collection 1990 (Box 108)
    - "Introduction" by Rita Mae Brown to Double for Death by Rex Stout 1994 (Box 108)
    - "Introduction" by Rita Mae Brown to Rubyfruit Jungle1988 Feb (Box 108)
    - Notes 1972 and n.d. (Box 108)
      re Ideology
    - Poetry ca. 1971-1973, n.d. (Box 108)
    - Short Story--"Dashing Through the Snow" in Horse Country1992 (Box 108)
    - Short Stories--"Red and Blue Air Mattress Piece" and "First Love" for Suddeutsche Zeitung 1994-1995 (Box 108)
    - Speeches 1974, n.d. (Box 108)
      re Sexuality, Revolution, etc.
    - Speeches--Santa Barbara Writers' Conference Address [ca. 1979?] (Box 108)
  - Literary Work by Other Authors
    - "Fluke" by Lisa Alexander, Tango Productions ca. 1990-1991 (Box 108)
    - "In Brief Time" by Carrie Alinn 1985 (Box 108)
    - "The Road to Destiny" by CeCe Bullard ca. 1994, 5 folders (Box 109)
    - The Voice of the River by Marjory Stoneman Douglas and Project Proposal 1987 and 1991, 2 folders (Box 109)
    - Alberta Hunter Story "I'm Having a Good Time" by Sheldon Epps, including correspondence with Rita Mae Brown 1990 (Box 109)
    - "Naked Eye" by Vicente Escriva n.d. (Box 110)
    - "What We Talk About When We Talk About Love" by Temple Fennell based on a Raymond Carver Story 1991 Nov 21 (Box 110)
    - "Boston" TV Series "Bible" by Richard Fielder 1987-1988 (Box 110)
    - "The Railroad Cafe A Novel Idea" Treatment by Fannie Flagg 1984 (Box 110)
    - "A Star in Behleham" by Josh Goldstein and Jonathan Prince 1997 Jun (Box 110)
    - Articles by Dolores Hayden 1976-1977 (Box 110)
    - Articles by Karl Hess 1978, n.d. (Box 110)
    - Making Out by Debbie Horsfield and Proposal by Franc Roddam 1989 and 1991, 2 folders (Box 110)
    - "My Patients Always Came First" by Herbert C. Jones, Jr. M.D. and Booton Herndon ca. 1989 (Box 111)
    - "Cry the Darkness" by Jud Kinberg 1992 Jul 24 (Box 111)
    - "Ex Mr. Winfield" by Bill and Jo LaMond 1990 (Box 111)
    - Short Stories by Tatyana Mamonova 1988-1989 (Box 111)
    - "Different" by Reg Marshall, Jr. with critique by Rita Mae Brown 1983 Oct. 25 (Box 111)
    - Articles by Miscellaneous Authors 1973-1986 (Box 111)
    - Articles by Ray Muessig 1976-1988, n.d. (Box 111)
    - "Shady Grove" by Frank Darius Namei and Robert Resnikoff n.d. (Box 111)
    - "Shell Game" Espisodes by Gerald Sanoff, Nick Thiel, and Clara Jean Wagner 1986, 3 folders (Box 112)
    - "The Formation of Lesbian Identity During the 'Coming Out' Process" by Elaine C. Spualding 1982, 2 folders (Box 112)
    - Articles and Papers by Julia P. Stanley 1971-1974, 2 folders (Box 112)
    - Rita Mae Brown Twayne Publishers by Carol M. Ward 1990, 1992-1993 (Box 112)
- Correspondence
  - Greeting Cards and Fan Mail
    - Correspondence--Birthday Cards 1985-1996, 9 folders (Box 113)
    - Correspondence--Fan Mail 1985 Mar-Jun, 2 folders (Box 113)
    - Correspondence--Fan Mail 1985 Jul-1986 May, 10 folders (Box 114)
    - Correspondence--Fan Mail 1986 Jun-Dec, 7 folders (Box 115)
    - Correspondence--Fan Mail 1987-1988 Jul, 8 folders (Box 116)
    - Correspondence--Fan Mail 1988 Aug-1989 Jan, 7 folders (Box 117)
    - Correspondence--Fan Mail 1989 Feb-Sep, 9 folders (Box 118)
    - Correspondence--Fan Mail 1989 Oct-1990 Jun, 10 folders (Box 119)
    - Correspondence--Fan Mail 1990 Jul-1991 Mar, 11 folders (Box 120)
    - Correspondence--Fan Mail 1991 Apr-Nov, 8 folders (Box 121)
    - Correspondence--Fan Mail 1991 Dec-1992 Oct, 10 folders (Box 122)
    - Correspondence--Fan Mail 1992 Nov-1993 Sep, 11 folders (Box 123)
    - Correspondence--Fan Mail 1993 Oct-1994 Jun, 8 folders (Box 124)
    - Correspondence--Fan Mail 1994 Jul-Dec, 8 folders (Box 125)
    - Correspondence--Fan Mail 1995 Jan-Apr, 7 folders (Box 126)
    - Correspondence--Fan Mail 1995 May-2001, n.d., 7 folders (Box 127)
    - Correspondence--Fan Mail--Form Letter Replies ca. 1990-1992 (Box 127)
    - Correspondence--Fan Mail--Individual 1991-1994 (Box 127)
    - Correspondence--Holiday Cards 1984 (Box 127)
    - Correspondence--Holiday Cards 1985-1988, 7 folders (Box 128)
    - Correspondence--Holiday Cards 1989-1992, 7 folders (Box 129)
    - Correspondence--Holiday Cards 1993-1998, 9 folders (Box 130)
    - Correspondence--Holiday Cards 1999-2001, n.d., 2 folders (Box 131)
  - Requests for Appearances, Comments, Donations, etc.
    - Correspondence--Requests 1978-1989 Aug, 7 folders (Box 131)
    - Correspondence--Requests 1989 Sep-1990, 7 folders (Box 132)
    - Correspondence--Requests 1991-1992, 7 folders (Box 133)
    - Correspondence--Requests 1993-1995 Aug, 6 folders (Box 134)
    - Correspondence--Requests 1995 Sep-1998, 7 folders (Box 135)
    - Correspondence--Requests 1999-2001, 3 folders (Box 136)
    - Correspondence--Requests--American Heart Association 1987-1994 (Box 136)
    - Correspondence--Requests--Authors Against Aids 1993-1994 (Box 136)
    - Correspondence--Requests--Borders Sales Meeting Conference 1994 Feb (Box 136)
    - Correspondence--Requests--Broward Public Library and National Writers' Workshop 1996 Apr (Box 136)
    - Correspondence--Requests--The Celluloid Closet 1992-1994 (Box 136)
    - Correspondence--Requests--Frankfurt Bookfair 1993 (Box 136)
    - Correspondence--Requests--Friends of Hilary Rosen Roast and Celebration 1995-1996 (Box 136)
    - Correspondence--Requests--The Furies Reunion (1996) 1995-1996 (Box 136)
    - Correspondence--Requests--Gay Games 1993-1994 (Box 137)
    - Correspondence--Requests--German Book Tour 1992, 2 folders (Box 137)
    - Correspondence--Requests--German Book Tour 1996 (Box 137)
    - Correspondence--Requests--GLAAD Media Awards, New York 1995-1996 (Box 137)
    - Correspondence--Requests--International Peace University 1994-1995 (Box 137)
    - Correspondence--Requests--Interviews 1989-2000, n.d., 2 folders (Box 137)
    - Correspondence--Requests--Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum Visit 1994 Oct (Box 137)
    - Correspondence--Requests--National Coalition Against Censorship Clear and Present Danger Benefit 1994-1995 (Box 137)
    - Correspondence--Requests--National Women's Music Festival 1994-1995 (Box 138)
    - Correspondence--Requests--National Writers' Workshop, The Salt Lake Tribune 1994-1995 (Box 138)
    - Correspondence--Requests--New Orleans Writers' Conference 1991-1994 (Box 138)
    - Correspondence--Requests--New York Public Library Literary Lions 1988-1994 (Box 138)
    - Correspondence--Requests--PEN/Faulkner Award 1994 (Box 138)
    - Correspondence--Requests--Penguin Music Classics 1998 (Box 138)
    - Correspondence--Requests for Quotes or Commentary About Other Author's Work 1984-2000, 3 folders (Box 138)
    - Correspondence--Rice University Writers' Conference 1996 (Box 138)
    - Correspondence--Requests--Richmond Organization for Sexual Minority Youth (R.O.S.M.Y.) 1994 (Box 138)
    - Correspondence--Requests--Rocky Mountain Book Festival 1993-1994 (Box 138)
    - Correspondence--Requests--Rowohlt Promotion Tour in Germany 1993-1994 (Box 138)
    - Correspondence--Requests--Southern Festival of Books 1991 (Box 138)
    - Correspondence--Requests--An Uncommon Legacy Foundation 1996 (Box 138)
    - Correspondence--Requests--Virginia Festival of the Book 1994-1995 (Box 139)
    - Correspondence--Requests--Virginia Heroes 1991-1993 (Box 139)
    - Correspondence--Requests--Wilson College Commencement Speaker and Honorary Degree Recipient 1992 (Box 139)
    - Correspondence--Requests--Writers and Books, Rochester, New York, Visiting Writers' Series 1995 (Box 139)
    - Correspondence--Requests--The Writer's Eye, Bayly Art Museum, Charlottesville, Virginia 1994-1995 (Box 139)
    - Correspondence--Requests-- A Writer's Guide to Great Books 1997-1998 (Box 139)
  - Personal Correspondence
    - Correspondence--Personal 1966-1984 Apr, 6 folders (Box 139)
    - Correspondence--Personal 1984 May--1986 Mar, 9 folders (Box 140)
    - Correspondence--Personal 1986 Apr-1987 Apr, 9 folders (Box 141)
    - Correspondence--Personal 1987 May-1988 Mar, 10 folders (Box 142)
    - Correspondence--Personal 1987 May-1988 Mar, 10 folders (Box 142)
    - Correspondence--Personal 1988 Apr-1989 Mar, 9 folders (Box 143)
    - Correspondence--Personal 1989 Apr-1990 Jul, 8 folders (Box 144)
    - Correspondence--Personal 1990 Aug-1991 Sep, 8 folders (Box 145)
    - Correspondence--Personal 1991 Oct-1993 Sep, 9 folders (Box 146)
    - Correspondence--Personal 1993 Oct-1994 Jul, 7 folders (Box 147)
    - Correspondence--Personal 1994 Aug-1995 Jun, 7 folders (Box 148)
    - Correspondence--Personal 1995 Jul-1996 Jun, 7 folders (Box 149)
    - Correspondence--Personal 1996 Jul-1997 Aug, 8 folders (Box 150)
    - Correspondence--Personal 1997 Sep-1999 Mar, 9 folders (Box 151)
    - Correspondence--Personal 1999 Apr-2001, n.d., 8 folders (Box 152)
  - Individual Correspondent Folders
    - Correspondence--Lisa Alexander 1986-1989 (Box 153)
    - Correspondence--Lisa Alther 1985-1994 (Box 153)
    - Correspondence--Larry Ashmead 1983-2000 (Box 153)
    - Correspondence--Authors ca. 1985-1995 (Box 153)
      including Ray Bradbury, Rita Dove, Bob Greene, Medeleine L'Engle, James A. Michener, Otto Penzler, and Linda Lightsey Rice
      arranged alphabetically
    - Correspondence--Ballantine Publishing Group 1994, 1994-2000 (Box 153)
    - Correspondence--Bantam Dell Publishing Group n.d. (Box 154)
    - Correspondence--Adrianne Blue 1994-1995 (Box 154)
    - Correspondence--Judy Blume 1986-1988, 1999 (Box 154)
    - Correspondence--Jeun and Claude Brown, Aunt and Uncle 1983-1993 (Box 154)
    - Correspondence--Julia Brown, mother of Rita Mae Brown 1966-1976 Jun, 6 folders (Box 154)
    - Correspondence--Julia Brown, mother of Rita Mae Brown 1976 Jul-1981, 8 folders (Box 155)
    - Correspondence--Julia Brown, mother of Rita Mae Brown 1982-1983, n.d., 5 folders (Box 156)
    - Correspondence--Gell Well Letters and Cards sent to Julia Brown, during her last illness 1983 Aug (Box 156)
    - Correspondence--Susan Brownmiller 1995 and 1999 (Box 156)
    - Correspondence--Elizabeth Bryant 1987-1997, 2 folders (Box 156)
    - Correspondence--Judy Chicago 1995 (Box 156)
    - Correspondence--Alvin Cooperman 1985-1989 (Box 157)
    - Correspondence--Julie Cypher 1994-1999 (Box 157)
    - Correspondence--Linda H. Damico, including letters from Rita Mae Brown 1975-1998, n.d., 4 folders (Box 157)
    - Correspondence--Sharon Deevey 1984-1987 (Box 157)
    - Correspondence--Carolyn Dow 1988-1991 (Box 157)
    - Correspondence--Mary Dundore "Aunt Mimi" 1970-1987, 2 folders (Box 157)
    - Correspondence--Mary Dundore "Aunt Mimi" 1988-1993, n.d. (Box 158)
    - Correspondence--Film Industry and Television 1972, 1981-2000, 4 folders (Box 158)
      including: Kate Clinton (1986 Apr 7 and 23, May 5, Jun 5); Glenn Close (1984 Jan 18); Bryant C. Gumbel (1983 Apr 27); Dudley Moore (1985 Sep 23 and 1986 Jan 22); Dolly Parton (n.d.); Lynn Redgrave (1986 Oct 6); Cybill Shepherd (1972 Jan 25 and Feb 1); Walter Slezak (1979 Feb 5); Alexis Smith (1972 Mar 3); and Helen "Gig" Smith (n.d.)
    - Correspondence--Jules Fisher 1981-1994 (Box 158)
    - Correspondence--Fannie Flagg 1978-1994, n.d. (Box 158)
    - Correspondence--Sally Gearhart, including letters from Rita Mae Brown 1972-1973 Mar (Box 158)
    - Correspondence--Sally Gearhart, including letters from Rita Mae Brown 1973 Apr-1998, n.d., 2 folders (Box 159)
    - Correspondence--David B. Goodstein 1983-1985 (Box 159)
    - Correspondence--Gross-Western Productions 1986-1989, 1997 (Box 159)